<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 17:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 17:35:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<title>Atlantic Tropical Weather Outlook</title>
<description>National Hurricane Center - Atlantic Tropical Weather Outlook</description>
<link>https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/</link>
<copyright>none</copyright>
<managingEditor>nhcwebmaster@noaa.gov (nhcwebmaster)</managingEditor>
<language>en-us</language>
<webMaster>nhcwebmaster@noaa.gov (nhcwebmaster)</webMaster>
<image>
<url>https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/gifs/xml_logo_nhc.gif</url>
<link>https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/</link>
<description>NOAA logo</description>
<title>Atlantic Tropical Weather Outlook</title>
<width>95</width>
<height>45</height>
</image>
<item>
<title>Atlantic Tropical Weather Outlook</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <br />
 000<br />
 ABNT20 KNHC 011735<br />
 TWOAT <br />
 <br />
 Tropical Weather Outlook<br />
 NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL<br />
 200 PM EDT Sun Sep 1 2019<br />
 <br />
 For the North Atlantic...Caribbean Sea and the Gulf of Mexico:<br />
 <br />
 The National Hurricane Center is issuing advisories on Hurricane<br />
 Dorian, located over the Abacos Islands.<br />
 <br />
 A broad area of low pressure centered near the Cabo Verde Islands is<br />
 producing a large area of showers and thunderstorms. This system is<br />
 showing signs of becoming better organized, and environmental<br />
 conditions appear conducive for additional development during the<br />
 next several days. A tropical depression is likely to form by the<br />
 middle of the week while the system moves generally northwestward<br />
 across the eastern tropical Atlantic Ocean. Heavy rainfall is<br />
 possible over portions of the southern Cabo Verde Islands during the<br />
 next day or so, and interests on those islands should monitor the<br />
 progress of this system.<br />
 * Formation chance through 48 hours...medium...60 percent.<br />
 * Formation chance through 5 days...high...70 percent.<br />
 <br />
 Another broad area of low pressure is located over the south-central<br />
 Gulf of Mexico. This disturbance continues to produce widespread<br />
 disorganized showers. Some gradual development of this system is<br />
 possible during the next few days while it moves slowly westward<br />
 across the southern and southwestern Gulf of Mexico toward the coast<br />
 of Mexico.<br />
 * Formation chance through 48 hours...low...20 percent.<br />
 * Formation chance through 5 days...low...30 percent.<br />
 <br />
 A trough of low pressure is located several hundred miles<br />
 south-southeast of Bermuda.  Although the associated shower and<br />
 thunderstorm activity is showing some signs of organization, the<br />
 system does not currently have a closed surface circulation. Some<br />
 gradual development of this disturbance is possible during the next<br />
 few days while it moves slowly northward or north-northwestward.<br />
 * Formation chance through 48 hours...low...10 percent.<br />
 * Formation chance through 5 days...low...30 percent.<br />
 <br />
 $$<br />
 Forecaster Zelinsky<br />
 ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 17:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
<link>https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/gtwo.php?basin=atlc</link>
<guid>201909011735</guid>
<author>nhcwebmaster@noaa.gov (nhcwebmaster)</author>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
