<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 17:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 17:46:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<title>Atlantic Hurricane Dorian Intermediate Advisory Number 33A </title>
<description>National Hurricane Center - Public Advisory for Atlantic wallet 5</description>
<link>https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/</link>
<copyright>none</copyright>
<managingEditor>nhcwebmaster@noaa.gov (nhcwebmaster)</managingEditor>
<language>en-us</language>
<webMaster>nhcwebmaster@noaa.gov (nhcwebmaster)</webMaster>
<image>
<url>https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/gifs/xml_logo_nhc.gif</url>
<link>https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/</link>
<description>NOAA logo</description>
<title>Atlantic Hurricane Dorian Intermediate Advisory Number 33A </title>
<width>95</width>
<height>45</height>
</image>
<item>
<title>Atlantic Hurricane Dorian Intermediate Advisory Number 33A </title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <br />
 000<br />
 WTNT35 KNHC 011746<br />
 TCPAT5<br />
 <br />
 BULLETIN<br />
 Hurricane Dorian Intermediate Advisory Number 33A<br />
 NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL052019<br />
 200 PM EDT Sun Sep 01 2019<br />
 <br />
 ...EYE OF CATASTROPHIC HURRICANE DORIAN OVER THE ABACOS ISLANDS IN<br />
 THE BAHAMAS...<br />
 ...HEADING WITH ALL ITS FURY TOWARD GRAND BAHAMA...<br />
 <br />
 <br />
 SUMMARY OF 200 PM EDT...1800 UTC...INFORMATION<br />
 ----------------------------------------------<br />
 LOCATION...26.5N 77.1W<br />
 ABOUT 0 MI...0 KM OVER GREAT ABACO ISLAND<br />
 ABOUT 185 MI...295 KM E OF WEST PALM BEACH FLORIDA<br />
 MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...185 MPH...295 KM/H<br />
 PRESENT MOVEMENT...W OR 270 DEGREES AT 7 MPH...11 KM/H<br />
 MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...911 MB...26.90 INCHES<br />
 <br />
 <br />
 WATCHES AND WARNINGS<br />
 --------------------<br />
 CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:<br />
 <br />
 None.<br />
 <br />
 SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:<br />
 <br />
 A Storm Surge Watch is in effect for...<br />
 * North of Deerfield Beach to the Volusia/Brevard County Line<br />
 <br />
 A Hurricane Warning is in effect for...<br />
 * Northwestern Bahamas excluding Andros Island<br />
 <br />
 A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...<br />
 * Andros Island<br />
 * North of Deerfield Beach to the Volusia/Brevard County Line<br />
 <br />
 A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...<br />
 * North of Deerfield Beach to Sebastian Inlet<br />
 <br />
 A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...<br />
 * North of Golden Beach to Deerfield Beach<br />
 * Lake Okeechobee<br />
 <br />
 A Storm Surge Watch means there is a possibility of life-<br />
 threatening inundation, from rising water moving inland from the<br />
 coastline, in the indicated locations during the next 48 hours.<br />
 For a depiction of areas at risk, please see the National Weather<br />
 Service Storm Surge Watch/Warning Graphic, available at<br />
 hurricanes.gov.<br />
 <br />
 A Hurricane Warning means that hurricane conditions are expected<br />
 somewhere within the warning area. Preparations to protect life and<br />
 property should be rushed to completion.<br />
 <br />
 A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible<br />
 within the watch area.  A watch is typically issued 48 hours<br />
 before the anticipated first occurrence of tropical-storm-force<br />
 winds, conditions that make outside preparations difficult or<br />
 dangerous.<br />
 <br />
 A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are<br />
 expected within the warning area within 36 hours.<br />
 <br />
 A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are<br />
 possible within the watch area, generally within 48 hours.<br />
 <br />
 Interests elsewhere along the east coast of Florida should continue<br />
 to monitor the progress of Dorian, as additional watches or<br />
 warnings may be required later today.<br />
 <br />
 For storm information specific to your area in the United States,<br />
 including possible inland watches and warnings, please monitor<br />
 products issued by your local National Weather Service forecast<br />
 office. For storm information specific to your area outside of the<br />
 United States, please monitor products issued by your national<br />
 meteorological service.<br />
 <br />
 <br />
 DISCUSSION AND OUTLOOK<br />
 ----------------------<br />
 At 200 PM EDT (1800 UTC), the extremely distinct eye of Hurricane<br />
 Dorian was located near latitude 26.5 North, longitude 77.1 West.<br />
 Dorian is moving toward the west near 7 mph (11 km/h). A slower<br />
 westward motion should continue for the next day or two, followed by<br />
 a gradual turn toward the northwest.  On this track, the core of<br />
 extremely dangerous Hurricane Dorian will continue to pound Great<br />
 Abaco today and the move near or over Grand Bahama Island tonight<br />
 and Monday. The hurricane should move closer to the Florida east<br />
 coast late Monday through Tuesday night.<br />
 <br />
 Maximum sustained winds are near 185 mph (295 km/h) with higher<br />
 gusts.  Dorian is a extremely dangerous category 5 hurricane on the<br />
 Saffir-Simpson Hurricane Wind Scale.  Some fluctuations in intensity<br />
 are likely, and Dorian is expected to remain a catastrophic<br />
 hurricane during the next few days.<br />
 <br />
 Hurricane-force winds extend outward up to 45 miles (75 km) from the<br />
 center and tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 140<br />
 miles (220 km).<br />
 <br />
 The minimum central pressure measured by both NOAA and Air Force<br />
 reconnaissance plane was 911 mb (26.90 inches).<br />
 <br />
 <br />
 HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND<br />
 ----------------------<br />
 WIND:  Catastrophic hurricane conditions are occurring in the Abacos<br />
 Islands and will spread across Grand Bahama Island later today and<br />
 tonight. Do not venture out into the eye, as winds will suddenly<br />
 increase as the eye passes.<br />
 <br />
 Hurricane conditions are possible within the hurricane watch area in<br />
 Florida by late Monday or early Tuesday.<br />
 <br />
 Tropical storm conditions are expected within the tropical storm<br />
 warning area on Monday and Tuesday.<br />
 <br />
 Tropical storm conditions are possible within the tropical storm<br />
 watch area by Monday night.<br />
 <br />
 STORM SURGE:  A life-threatening storm surge will raise water levels<br />
 by as much as 18 to 23 feet above normal tide levels in areas of<br />
 onshore winds on the Abaco Islands and Grand Bahama Island.  Near<br />
 the coast, the surge will be accompanied by large and destructive<br />
 waves.<br />
 <br />
 The combination of a dangerous storm surge and the tide will cause<br />
 normally dry areas near the coast to be flooded by rising waters<br />
 moving inland from the shoreline. The water could reach the<br />
 following heights above ground somewhere in the indicated<br />
 areas if the peak surge occurs at the time of high tide...<br />
 <br />
 Volusia/Brevard County Line to Jupiter Inlet FL...4 to 7 ft<br />
 North of Deerfield Beach to Jupiter Inlet FL...2 to 4 ft<br />
 <br />
 The surge will be accompanied by large and destructive waves.<br />
 Surge-related flooding depends on the how close the center of<br />
 Dorian comes to the Florida east coast, and can vary greatly over<br />
 short distances.  For information specific to your area, please see<br />
 products issued by your local National Weather Service forecast<br />
 office.<br />
 <br />
 RAINFALL:  Dorian is expected to produce the following rainfall<br />
 totals through late this week:<br />
 <br />
 Northwestern Bahamas...12 to 24 inches, isolated 30 inches.<br />
 Coastal Carolinas...5 to 10 inches, isolated 15 inches.<br />
 Central Bahamas and the Atlantic Coast from the Florida peninsula<br />
 through Georgia...2 to 4 inches, isolated 6 inches.<br />
 <br />
 This rainfall may cause life-threatening flash floods.<br />
 <br />
 SURF:  Large swells are already affecting east-facing shores of the<br />
 Bahamas, the Florida east coast, and will spread northward along the<br />
 southeastern United States coast during the next few days.  These<br />
 swells are likely to cause life-threatening surf and rip current<br />
 conditions.  Please consult products from your local weather office.<br />
 <br />
 <br />
 NEXT ADVISORY<br />
 -------------<br />
 Next complete advisory at 500 PM EDT.<br />
 <br />
 Hourly Tropical Cyclone Update statements will begin at 300 PM EDT.<br />
 <br />
 $$<br />
 Forecaster Avila<br />
 <br />
 ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 17:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
<link>https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/MIATCPAT5.shtml</link>
<guid>201909011746</guid>
<author>nhcwebmaster@noaa.gov (nhcwebmaster)</author>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
