<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 14:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 14:57:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<title>Atlantic Hurricane Dorian Discussion Number 33 </title>
<description>National Hurricane Center - Discussion for Atlantic wallet 5</description>
<link>https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/</link>
<copyright>none</copyright>
<managingEditor>nhcwebmaster@noaa.gov (nhcwebmaster)</managingEditor>
<language>en-us</language>
<webMaster>nhcwebmaster@noaa.gov (nhcwebmaster)</webMaster>
<image>
<url>https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/gifs/xml_logo_nhc.gif</url>
<link>https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/</link>
<description>NOAA logo</description>
<title>Atlantic Hurricane Dorian Discussion Number 33 </title>
<width>95</width>
<height>45</height>
</image>
<item>
<title>Atlantic Hurricane Dorian Discussion Number 33 </title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <br />
 000<br />
 WTNT45 KNHC 011457<br />
 TCDAT5<br />
 <br />
 Hurricane Dorian Discussion Number  33<br />
 NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL052019<br />
 1100 AM EDT Sun Sep 01 2019<br />
 <br />
 Air Force and NOAA reconnaissance planes penetrated the distinct<br />
 eye of Dorian, and found that the hurricane has become extremely<br />
 intense with a stadium effect in the eye. The NOAA plane reported a<br />
 peak flight-level wind of 159 kt, while the SFMR from both planes<br />
 have measured winds between 155 and 170 kt.  A dropsonde from the<br />
 NOAA plane measured a wind gust of 176 kt at the surface. A blend of<br />
 these measurements yield to an initial intensity of 155 kt, making<br />
 Dorian the strongest hurricane on record in the northwestern<br />
 Bahamas.<br />
 <br />
 For the next few days, Dorian should experience some fluctuations in<br />
 intensity, and in addition to eyewall replacement cyclone, the<br />
 interaction with the northwestern Bahamas should weaken the<br />
 hurricane slightly. After 3 days, as Dorian moves northward along<br />
 or offshore of southeast United States coast, the shear is forecast<br />
 to increase, resulting in a more distinct gradual weakening.<br />
 <br />
 Reconnaissance plane and satellite fixes indicate that Dorian, as<br />
 anticipated, has slowed down and is moving toward the west or 270<br />
 degrees at 6 kt. The steering currents are collapsing and Dorian is<br />
 expected to slow down even more, prolonging its catastrophic effects<br />
 in the northwestern Bahamas. The NHC forecast calls for a slow west<br />
 to west-northwest motion during the next 48 hours, with a turn to<br />
 the north and an increase in forward speed as the mid-level trough<br />
 along the eastern United States deepens and becomes the dominant<br />
 steering feature. The current forecast is only a few miles west of<br />
 the previous one and is basically on top of the multi-model<br />
 consensus. Both the deterministic and consensus tracks have shown<br />
 the usual variability to the right or to the left from run to run,<br />
 but the overall trend is for the hurricane to turn northward<br />
 offshore but very close to the Florida peninsula.<br />
 <br />
 Given the uncertainty in the track forecast and the anticipated<br />
 increase in size of the hurricane, a Hurricane Watch and Storm<br />
 Surge Watch have been issued for a portion of the east Florida<br />
 coast. It is emphasized that although the official track forecast<br />
 does not show landfall, users should not focus on the exact track. A<br />
 small deviation to the left of the track could bring the intense<br />
 core of the hurricane its dangerous winds closer to or onto the<br />
 coast.<br />
 <br />
 Key Messages:<br />
 <br />
 1. A prolonged period of catastrophic winds and storm surge will<br />
 affect the Abaco Islands today. Everyone there should take immediate<br />
 shelter and not venture into the eye. These catastrophic conditions<br />
 are likely on Grand Bahama Island later today or tonight, and<br />
 efforts to protect life and property there should be rushed to<br />
 completion.<br />
 <br />
 2. Storm surge and hurricane watches and tropical storm warnings are<br />
 in effect for portions of the Florida east coast. Life-threatening<br />
 storm surge and dangerous hurricane-force winds are possible along<br />
 portions of the Florida east coast through mid-week, as only a<br />
 slight deviation to the left of the official forecast would bring<br />
 the core of Dorian near or over the coast. Residents should listen<br />
 to advice given by local emergency officials.<br />
 <br />
 3. There is an increasing likelihood of strong winds and dangerous<br />
 storm surge along the coasts of Georgia, South Carolina, and North<br />
 Carolina later this week. Residents in these areas should continue<br />
 to monitor the progress of Dorian.<br />
 <br />
 4. Heavy rains, capable of producing life-threatening flash floods,<br />
 are possible over northern portions of the Bahamas and coastal<br />
 sections of the southeast and lower mid-Atlantic regions of the<br />
 United States through late this week.<br />
 <br />
 FORECAST POSITIONS AND MAX WINDS<br />
 <br />
 INIT  01/1500Z 26.5N  76.8W  155 KT 180 MPH<br />
  12H  02/0000Z 26.6N  77.7W  150 KT 175 MPH<br />
  24H  02/1200Z 26.8N  78.5W  145 KT 165 MPH<br />
  36H  03/0000Z 27.0N  79.0W  135 KT 155 MPH<br />
  48H  03/1200Z 27.4N  79.4W  120 KT 140 MPH<br />
  72H  04/1200Z 29.7N  80.2W  100 KT 115 MPH<br />
  96H  05/1200Z 32.5N  79.0W   85 KT 100 MPH<br />
 120H  06/1200Z 35.5N  74.5W   80 KT  90 MPH<br />
 <br />
 $$<br />
 Forecaster Avila<br />
 <br />
 ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 14:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
<link>https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/MIATCDAT5.shtml</link>
<guid>201909011457</guid>
<author>nhcwebmaster@noaa.gov (nhcwebmaster)</author>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
